Removing Bumblebee and replacing him with...
删除大黄蜂 再替换上…
The tap-dancing monkey strikes again.
踢踏舞猴子再度登场！
Bumblebee sightings on the world wide web are no laughing matter.
大黄蜂在互联网上抛头露面不是什么好笑的事
7... 8... 9...
7 8 9…
Why can't I just drive from now on?
我就不能只开车吗？
Because your legs will atrophy if you choose not to use them.
要是不用你的腿 它们会萎缩的
Oh...
噢…
1... 2... 3...
1 2 3…
Wait. What's that?
等等 那是什么？
A Cybertronian escape pod?
塞博特恩的逃生舱？
Here in Earth's atmosphere?
在地球大气层里？
Autobot or Decepticon?
汽车人还是霸天虎？
Impossible to tell, given the image resolution.
图片很模糊 没法辨认
In any event, this merits investigation.
不管哪种情况我们都应调查一番
Could be a trap, and we're down one bot.
没准是个圈套 此外我们还倒下一位
Should we reach out to Wheeljack?
需要联系千斤顶吗？
I can hear you!
我听到了…
I don't care if Bulkhead isn't combat-ready.
我不管隔板是否能参加战斗
After that revenge stunt he pulled with Miko, Wheeljack can stay rogue.
鉴于上次千斤顶和神子一手导演的复仇大戏 他还是去当世外高人吧
An Autobot may be in distress.
可能是一个遇难的汽车人
Ratchet, bring your medical kit.
救护车 带上你的医疗箱
It is of Decepticon origin.
是霸天虎那边的
And the Con inside blew his way out.
里面的虎子已经跑路了
All those Cons came out of one pod?
那些虎子都是从一个舱里生出来的？
The humans refer to the phenomenon as a clown car.
按人类的说法 这是“英雄妈妈”
Incoming!
有人过来了！
Down in front!
前面的趴下！
Friendly?
自己人？
Fall back!
后退！
Whoo! Too hot for you, Cons?!
哇噢 烫不烫 虎子们？
Friend of yours?
你的朋友？
Never seen him before.
从没见过他
Torching that Energon leak.
点燃泄漏的能量
Pretty good plan, right?
我的点子不错吧？
Except that it wasn't your plan.
只不过那不是你的点子
It was a random shot that almost fried us to a crisp.
那不过是流弹造成的 而且差点连我们也一起烤糊了
Worked out, didn't it?
它管用了 不是吗？
Thank you, fellow Autobot.
谢谢你 汽车人同伴
Your... valor... is to be commended.
你的…勇气值得嘉奖
I... don't believe it.
我…难以置信！
Y-You're Optimus Prime! He's Optimus Prime!
你是擎天柱！他是擎天柱！
- We know. - Yes, yes... yes.
- 我们知道 - 是啊是的
What is your name, soldier?
你叫什么名字 战士？
Smokescreen, sir.
烟幕 长官！
Welcome to Earth, Smokescreen.
欢迎来到地球 烟幕！
It's an honor to be here...
来到这里是我的荣幸
Especially with you.
尤其是能与您并肩战斗
Now what? It's not like we can just bring him back to base.
现在呢？我们不可能就这么带他回基地
Wouldn't be the first time an ally turned out to be a plant.
我们有过被间谍“鱼目混珠”的先例
I see that you received your training from Cybertron's Elite Guard.
看起来你在塞博特恩的精英卫队中接受过训练
True enough... though it wasn't more than a boot camp by the time I joined.
没错 不过那儿和新兵训练营差不多
I never even got a proper graduation ceremony.
连个像样的毕业典礼都没有
There was a war going on.
那是在战争时期！
Hey, all I ever wanted was to be a soldier,
嘿 我不过是想成为一名战士
serve the Autobot cause.
为汽车人事业而献身
But what I got was security detail at Iacon.
不过我最终却成为了一名铁堡的保安特遣队员！
The Hall of Records of all places?
中央档案馆？
Optimus, do you not find this highly suspicious?
擎天柱 你不觉得这很可疑吗？
Smokescreen, what was your assignment inside the hall?
烟幕 你在档案馆的任务是什么？
Guarding Alpha Trion during what turned out to be the final days of the war.
当战争进入末期时负责护卫钛师傅
You served under the master archivist?
你直属于主档案保管员？
Eh, I wasn't thrilled at first...
刚开始我很不开心
watching the back of an old bot instead of kicking Con tailpipe.
不能去痛扁虎子 却要看着一个老头的背影
Sorry. But the big "A" turned out to be a great teacher and a... true friend.
对不起 不过钛师傅真的是个良师…益友
I mean, he was the one who petitioned Halogen and the High Council to make you a Prime.
我是说 就是他在最高议会面前推举你为领袖的
Rafael... activate the ground bridge.
拉斐尔 启动环陆桥
That's it?
这就行了？
That's all you need to hear before inviting him to the party?
就凭这几句话你就让他入伙了？
If my former mentor shared this information,
既然我的导师愿意与他分享这些信息
it is because he considered Smokescreen a trusted ally.
就足以证明烟幕是可以信赖的伙伴
We haven't had somebody new here since Wheeljack.
在千斤顶之后我们就再也没有新人入伙了！
What's your story, Smoke?
你的故事 烟幕？
Where'd you come from? How'd you get here?
你从哪里来？怎么到这儿的？
How many blasters you packin'?
你带了多少武器？
So, these are the life-force we're supposed to protect?
这些就是我们要保护的生物？
Are they all like this?
他们都是这个样子的？
Fortunately not...
幸运的是并非如此
but I too share Miko's fascination with how you came to arrive on Earth.
不过我和神子一样好奇你是怎么来到地球的？
In a Decepticon escape pod.
搭一艘霸天虎的逃生舱
Still got trust issues, huh? Tough crowd.
还是不信任我是吧？真难相处
The main thrust of combat operations was at least 20 clicks from the Hall of Records,
主战斗地点离档案馆至少有20公里
so things had been pretty quiet.
所以那里一度很平静
But the situation went downhill fast.
然而局势很快便急转直下
The Cons launched a massive surge that wiped out the last line of defenses surrounding Iacon.
虎子们发动了一次大规模攻击 击溃了铁堡外部的最后防线
I was the only thing left to them back,
我是最后一个可以进行抵抗的人
and, let me tell you, I was pumped.
我得说 我尽力了！
I mean, this was my chance to see real action for the first time...
我是说 这是我第一次有机会参见真正的战斗！
to prove myself.
来证明我自己
Until everything went black.
直到我失去了意识
Cons took me prisoner and dumped me onto a transport ship.
虎子们俘获了我 并将我绑到一艘运输船上
But I managed to give a guard the slip and hopped in an escape pod.
不过我趁守卫不备钻进了一个逃生舱
Apparently, it was a long-distance pod, 'cause it knocked me into stasis.
很显然这是一个长距离逃生舱 它令我进入了休眠状态
Next thing I knew, I'm hitting solid ground... hard.
等到我再次醒来的时候 正好重重摔落在地上
The Decepticon warship must have picked up pod's beacon and guided it to Earth.
霸天虎的战舰一定识别了逃生舱的信号 并引导它来到了地球！
Which would explain Smokescreen's welcoming committee.
这就解释了虎子们为什么会来迎接烟幕
Bet those Cons were disappointed not to find one of their own inside.
那些虎子发现里面不是他们的同伙一定很失望
Smokescreen, do you know of Alpha Ttrion's fate,
烟幕 你知道在铁堡失守后
after the fall of Iacon?
钛师傅怎么样了吗？
I wish I did.
我也想知道
But that was the last I ever saw of him.
不过那是我最后一次见到他老人家
That's it... my life story.
这就是我的故事
Not exactly the glory I envisioned for myself
不像我梦想的那般荣耀
... until now.
不过现在
Being here with Optimus Prime...
跟擎天柱在一起？
I knew I was destined for great things.
我就知道我注定是块做大事的料
I mean, now that you have help,
我是说 现在你有帮手了
how hard could it be to end this war?
结束这场战争能有多困难？
Take a good look, Newbie.
好好看看这个 新来的！
This is how hard.
就有这么难！
Smokescreen, I would suggest that you take some time to become acclimated to your new surroundings.
烟幕 我建议你花点时间适应下新环境
A tour of the base would be an excellent start.
参观下基地是个不错的开始
Sure thing!
没问题！
I mean... Jack here offers a very informative tour.
我的意思是 杰克可以提供一个内容丰富的旅程
This is what the humans call "the information superhighway".
这就是人类所谓的信息高速公路
A trillion gigabytes of data... none of it's useful!
一万亿个字节 没一个有用的！
Though some oddly engrossing.
尽管有些吸引人的奇怪东西
What is this?
这是什么？
Ah... ignorant life-forms have no idea what they've uncovered.
啊… 愚蠢的生命体不知道他们找到的是什么
Red Energon.
红色能量
If I can possess its power,
如果我能拥有它的力量
not only will I be stronger but also faster.
我不仅能变得更强壮 也能变得更快
Significantly faster.
大大的加快！
Phase shifter... Spark extractor... Immobilizer...
相位仪 火种剥离器 静止器
this is where we store the Cybertronian relics we found buried on Earth.
这里保存的都是我们找到的埋藏在地球上的遗物
And talk about a small universe 'cause most of them came from the...
说起来世界真是小 因为这些大部分都来自…
The Iacon hall of records.
铁堡档案馆
I remember these.
我记得这些
Whoa. What kind of relic is she?
哇哦！她算哪种遗物？
The kind you don't want to mess with.
你最好别招惹的那种
If you wanted to replace me, you should have called Wheeljack.
如果你们想换掉我 最好叫千斤顶来！
I could have lived with that.
那样我还能好受些
No one is replacing you, Bulkhead.
没人要换掉你 隔板
For one thing, Smokescreen's too green.
况且烟幕还是个楞头青
Well, Bulk's as green as they get.
隔板也够青
What Arcee means is...
阿尔茜的意思是
Smokescreen still has a great deal to learn.
烟幕需要学习的事情还有很多！
And once you got him trained, then what, huh?
那训练好他之后呢？
He's in. I'm a doorstop.
他入伍？我退役？
Bulkhead, your place with us is not in jeopardy,
隔板 你在我们中的位置不会受到任何影响
but there is no dispute that we have long required additional firepower.
但毫无疑问的是 我们长久以来缺乏战斗力
It is essential that our team learns to work with our new recruit,
对于我们的队伍来说 现在应学会接纳新人
not against him.
而不是排斥他
Better hope the hotshot's blasters are as big as his mouth.
但愿这小子的枪跟嘴一样厉害
How hard can it be?
这有什么难的…
Hey, everyone. Check this out.
嘿 伙计们 看看这个
But don't tell me it's another Bumblebee sight... oh my.
别告诉我又是大黄蜂目击新闻！哦 天啊！
Red Energon.
红色能量
Here... on Earth?
在地球上？
What's Red Energon?
红色能量是什么？
An extremely rare and volatile form of Energellum.
一种十分稀有且极不稳定的能量形式
Refined into fuel, it provides the power of hyperspeed.
提炼出的燃料可以提供超高速
We must have Agent Fowler clear the dig site of all human presence
我们必须联系福勒探员 让他疏散挖掘地点附近的所有人类
in the event we are not the only ones who have discovered its location.
我们不可能是唯一发现这个地点的人
Now you're talking.
说得好
Let's scramble up some Cons' circuits.
我们去打烂虎子的电路！
Given your limited field experience,
鉴于你的实战经验有限
I believe further training is required before you are battle-ready.
我认为在参加战斗之前 你有必要接受更多的训练
Optimus, with all due respect...
擎天柱 恕我直言…
Furthermore, we Autobots live on this planet as robots in disguise.
此外 我们汽车人在地球上需要隐蔽
You will need to obtain an Earth-based vehicle mode.
你需要扫描一个地球的车辆形态
In order to maintain a low profile...
为了保持低调行动
if that's possible for you.
如果你能做得到的话
If you're talking wheels, bring 'em on!
你是说变车是吧？没问题！
The Red Energon is mine, humans!
红色能量是我的 人类！
For you are powerless in the face of the mighty Star...
你们毫无胜算 因为你们面对的是伟大的红蜘…
What?
什么？
Where is it?
它哪儿去了？
Nope.
不行
How about that one?
那个怎么样？
Eh, it's more Ratchet's speed, don't you think?
呃 那速度更适合救护车 你不觉得吗？
Cement truck?
水泥车？
Yeah, if I were a Constructicon.
好吧 除非我是个挖地虎
Seriously, this is the best your planet has to offer?
老实说 这就是你们星球最拿得出手的？
No, but this is Jasper.
不 这里毕竟是贾斯帕
I feel for you.
我找到了
Fowler couldn't have the crane operator lower the thing?
福勒就不能用吊车把它放下来吗？
The humans must have been preparing to transfer the meteor to a cargo ship
一定是人类准备把陨石装上货轮的时候
when they received his evacuation order.
接到了疏散指令
Run along home, Autobots.
滚回去 汽车人！
That Red Energon has my name all over it.
那个红色能量本座指名要了！
And I am more than willing to fight for it.
并且我不惜为它而战！
Secure the Red Energon and have Ratchet bridge it back to base.
夺取红色能量 叫救护车把它传送回基地
Don't tell me you've already forgotten our last encounter, Prime.
别告诉我你忘了我们上次的交手了 擎天柱！
Keep moving, Bee.
继续前进 小蜂！
Optimus, is something wrong?
擎天柱 出什么情况了吗？
Starscream has come for the Red Energon,
红蜘蛛来抢夺红色能量
and I fear he will not be deterred in his quest.
恐怕没法让他打消这个念头
Starscream? I heard stories about that stiletto-heeled creep back on Cybertron.
红蜘蛛？我在塞博特恩听说过那个穿高跟鞋的家伙
Send me in, Doc.
让我过去 医生！
When Optimus requires backup, he will ask for it.
如果擎天柱需要救援 他会提出的
Aw, come on. I got my V-mode and everything.
噢 拜托 我已经准备好车辆形态了
I'm souped up and ready to roll.
开足马力就等着出发了
Eh! Eh! Eh!
打住！打住！
What part of "further training" did you not understand?
更多的训练你听不懂吗？
The higher you climb, the harder you fall.
爬得越高 摔得越惨！
Haha. Autobots... such slow learners.
哈哈 汽车人 总是不长记性
Optimus, what is your status?
擎天柱 你的情况怎么样？
Ratchet, they need me. I can do this.
救护车 他们需要我 我能行的！
Arcee? Bumblebee?
阿尔茜？大黄蜂？
Did you hear what I said?
你听到我在说话了吗？
I heard, and I'm ignoring you.
我听到了 但是没有理睬你
This may be your opportunity after all, Smokescre...
看来你终于有机会了 烟幕…
Where is Smokescreen?
烟幕呢？
That's the one.
就是这个
You, there!
你！
What in the name of the Allspark do you think you're doing?
看在火种源的份上 你知道你在做什么吗？
Time to unload some more deadweight.
要扔些重物下去了
Watch your step, Autobots!
站稳了 汽车人！
Apparently, no one defined "low profile" for him.
很显然没人告诉他“低调”是什么意思
So, the Autobots have a new recruit.
看来 汽车人有个新兵蛋子
And you must be Starscream.
你就是红蜘蛛啊
I thought you'd be taller.
还以为有多高大呢
This will not end well.
这下可不好收场了
Smokescreen, stand down.
烟幕 退下！
You are no match for Starscream's Apex armor.
你敌不过红蜘蛛的精锐护甲
Any last words, Smokescreen?
有什么遗言吗 烟幕？
Just four: kiss your armor goodbye!
八个字：和你的盔甲吻别吧
A Phase shifter?
相位仪？
Now, that was a plan!
这可是个好点子！
You aren't the only one sporting a fancy wrist-mounted device.
你可不是唯一一个带着腕式装备的人！
Think fast!
动动脑筋吧！
No!
不！
Told you I just needed to borrow it for a while.
都说了不过是借用一会儿！
Doc here thought I was trying to steal your relics.
医生却认为我要偷你们的遗物
Only until you explained your plan,
除非你先解释你的计划
which I then sanctioned.
而后得到我的批准
It's called protocol.
这叫做协议
Ratchet is correct.
救护车是对的
Standard procedure must be observed by every member of this team.
规则适用于队伍中的所有成员
However... I believe we must also commend Smokescreen.
不过 我相信烟幕是值得称赞的
You have proven to be a quick study by choosing to place strategy above bravado.
你在选择策略制造声势方面学习的很快
There is gonna be no living with him now.
看来要开始和他一起生活了
While this may lack the pageantry of a proper Elite Guard ceremony,
虽然这个仪式不如精英卫队那样壮观
I wish to welcome you to team Prime.
我真诚地欢迎你加入领袖卫队！
The Newbie did all right.
这个新人确实干得不赖…
Don't worry, Bulk.
别担心 小隔
He's got nothing on you.
他不会抢你的饭碗的！
Seriously, once we get that leg of yours back in shape,
真的 一旦你的腿伤愈复出了
old Smokey's gonna learn real quick who the top wrecking ball is run here.
烟幕就会知道谁是这里最强的粉碎球了！
Bulkhead?
隔板？